Dave J. Horrocks

Full Stack Software Developer

Details

@ Email

daveyj.dh@googlemail.com

J Phone

+44(0)7889173482

Address

 18 Norfolk Road Portishead BS20 6YA England

Date of Birth

02 - 05 - 1990

@ Links

- GitHub
- LinkedIn

✓ Skills

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Mathematical Skill
- Interpretation of Requirements
- Problem-solving Abilities
- Cross-discipline Communication
- Logical Thinking

Spoken Languages

- English (native)
- German (dilettante)

Profile

Professional and personable worker with a great ability to learn, communicate and interpret. Well organised and efficient. Very comfortable with responsibility and new challenges. High attention to detail and always striving for perfection. Happy working alone and as part of a team.

I have worked in a variety of industries throughout my occupational life. I enjoy a challenge and have always striven to perform to an exceptional level within any role presented to me. I learn quickly and am a firm believer that a better comprehension of systems enables me to push the boundaries of capabilities.

New into the software industry, hoping to bring skills developed in other occupations in to the fast-paced world of software development.

Courses

Full Stack Software Development - E-Commerce Applications - Code Institute - Online

Apr 2021 - Mar 2022

Accreditations

Milestone Systems Certified Integration Technician

Apr 2018 - Apr 2020

Milestone Systems Certified Design Engineer

Apr 2018 - Apr 2018

Fire Industry Association – Detection Design

Jun 2015

Fire Industry Association – Installation & Testing

Jul 2015

Employment History

First entry intentionally out of sequence as it has more relevant skills

Security Systems Engineer - Astron Fire and Security Ltd. - Bristol

Apr 2015 - Mar 2019

A fantastic fire and security company, allowing me to further develop logic and problem solving skills. Having started with no experience in the industry, I quickly became very competent with a multitude of systems and continued to further my skills.

- Milestone Systems accredited design and installation engineer
- Complex fire alarm and intruder alarm cause and effect programming
- Integration between IP, digital and analogue systems
- Access control logic programming with check controls
- Health and safety representative for engineering team within company
- Install, maintain, repair and upkeep a variety of intruder alarm, fire alarm/life safety, staff attack and CCTV/IP video systems and access control equipment
- Detailed report writing, with findings, recommendations and equipment used/required
- Work in large teams as leading engineer, alone as independent worker and liaise with third party companies when necessary
- Give practical demonstrations of equipment to clients, including the explanation of safety requirements and legal obligations involved with safety systems
- Out of hours rota for 'on call' work, roughly 1 week in 4
- International operations when necessary (Europe)

Sheet Metal Fabricator - Steel Frog Ltd. - Weston-Super-Mare

Mar 2020 - May 2021

A small, bespoke, metal fabrication company with an absolutely astounding reputation for perfect finishes to products and innovative problem's solutions.

- Reduced operation times by editing G Code files to speed up repetitive processes
- Operate CNC machinery for processing sheet metal
- Fabricate bespoke furniture from sheet metal
- Metalworking skills (welding, grinding, polishing, etc.)
- Work within fine tolerances (0.2mm) and project deadlines
- Update workshop layout with employer, utilising existing skills, to create a more efficient work flow
- Deliver stock to clients as and when necessary

Personal Mechanic/Sales Prep - Copper Spark - Nailsea

Mar 2019 - Mar 2020

A wonderful opportunity to work with some classic race cars, unique vehicles and intricate problems. All levels of work undertaken. A loan worker in the workshop with a hefty workload to be maintained and organised by myself.

- Maintain and modify personal racing cars as required
- Various and extensive levels of maintenance and repair work to light vehicles, generally being prepared for sale (mechanical, electrical and aesthetics)
- Maintain stock levels of consumable items and ensure required parts ordered in a timely fashion

- Check all vehicles for safety and road-worthiness
- Organise job priorities and time frames with no managerial input

Workshop Manager - First Call Ltd. - Nailsea

Apr 2013 - Mar 2015

A very busy German car specialist garage, managing a small team of technicians to provide service to an impeccable standard.

- Organise client bookings and ensure workload appropriate for the workshop
- Oversee technicians in the workshop and assist when necessary
- Maintain stock levels for smooth business operation
- Update clients with timescales, findings and cost implications as work carried out
- Generate invoices and maintain good customer relations
- Ensure good, safe working practices followed in the workshop
- Interpret technical reports from technicians to allow recommendations to be written to clients without confusion
- Interpret reported issues with vehicles from customers to ensure the correct complaint is being addressed
- Carry out more complex fault finding/repair work if above competency level of service technicians
- Electrical diagnosis and repair work
- Aid junior technicians with their learning processes

(Apprentice) Mechanic / Office Administrator - Gordano Motor Services - Weston-in-Gordano

Apr 2008 - Mar 2013

A local garage with a high turnover of work. Soon into my time here, my employer and I were the only staff and so I learnt the trade fast and had to help with all aspects of the business.

- Attend Bridgwater college to work toward, and achieve, NVQ Lvl 3 in light motor vehicle maintenance and repair - advanced apprenticeship
- Update clients with timescales, findings and cost implications as work carried out
- Generate invoices using digital invoicing system
- Maintain good customer relations
- Learn the mechanics trade while working within a small, busy workshop
- Assist with MOT testing and bodywork preparation as necessary
- Collect and drop off customers to home/work addresses
- Order and maintain stock levels from a variety of suppliers

During my time in this employment, I was successful in winning the Autoskills UK competition. This is a competition for apprentice mechanics which rewards applicants for knowledge and skills, as well as good working practices, including professionalism and safe working. It is a national competition and I was very pleased to finish in 1st place in the UK in 2011

Education

Lvl 3 NVQ/Diploma - Advanced Light Vehicle Maintenance and Repair - Bridgwater College

Sep 2009 - Jun 2012

GCSEs - Gordano School

Sep 2001 - Jun 2006

11 GCSEs, grades A* - C

- Electronic Products A*
- Mathematics A
- Statistics A
- English C
- German A

References

Helen van Laun - Astron Fire and Security

helen@astronfireandsecurity.co.uk | +44(0)1275 373 098

Mike Williams - Copper Spark

copperspark66@gmail.com | +44(0)7813 173 066

Garry Scutt - Gordano Motor Services

+44(0)1275 842 690

Extra-Curricular Activities

Committee Member - BS20 Bar / Portishead Working Men's Club

2017 - 2020

Active member helping with repairs and general operations at my local working men's club. Assisted with the transition into an 'all-welcome' sports bar facility. Although I do not drink alcohol, many members of the local community frequent the premises and this was a great way to socialise and give something back to the community.

Trainee Rower - Portishead Pilot Gig Rowing Club

2019 - 2020

An old passion, reignited by a desire to maintain fitness. Unfortunately, work related injuries and complications resulted in a short-lived attendance, but I continue to support and assist the club in any way I can.

Hobbies and Interests

I thoroughly enjoy cooking, listening to music, and playing card and board games. I walk often and enjoy the fresh air as much as I can. I enjoy riding my motorbike and maintaining my vehicles, as well as a few friend's.

I play a few video games and really hope to make more of my own in the future. My first coding exposure was working with Unity, creating a very basic 2D platform game. I would love to continue this passion in my leisure time as my skill-set develops.

I also thoroughly enjoy helping other people learn.

Medical

Type 1 Diabetic - Insulin Controlled (diag. 2000)

Thank you for your consideration